core-econ.org 2019-12-25

# Privacy policy - CORE

**Personal data**

You don’t have to create an account or provide us with any personal information to access the CORE website or ebooks. However, we will ask for some personal details if you wish to access additional resources. This information will be obtained via our website’s registration form only.

The personal data we store and process will include:

  * your name,
  * your email address,
  * your student or teacher status,
  * name of your institution or university, city and country.

By registering on the CORE website you agree for this data to be held in the CORE database. As registration data is needed to provide you with access to additional resources we will hold it until you notify us to delete your account.

**Other data**

When you provide us with your contact details you will be asked whether you wish to receive any further communications from us. You will also have the option of subscribing for CORE updates. If you agreed to receive further communications from CORE, from time to time we might send you useful information about the services we offer, new materials we published on the CORE website, or to request feedback on our material and information about the course you are teaching. By subscribing to further communications from CORE you agree for this data to be held in the CORE database. We will hold it until you unsubscribe or until you notify us to delete your account.

When you answer the questions module in the CORE ebooks or the quizzes module on the CORE website the record of your answers will be saved in your account held on the CORE database. The record will only note if a particular question has been answered correctly or incorrectly for the purpose of keeping a score on the quiz module on the CORE website. By answering the questions and quizzes you agree for this data to be held in the CORE database. We will hold it until you notify us to delete your account.

**Visits to CORE website**

When you log in to your account on the CORE website, and every subsequent time you visit our site, a record of the date of your visit is logged in your account held on the CORE database. The purpose of this record is to display, in your account page, the last time you have visited the website. We will hold this data until you notify us to delete your account.

When you visit the CORE website we may collect non-personally-identifiable information relating to your use of our site via Google Analytics technology. This may include: which pages you see, how long you stay, what you click on our pages, if you visit the website again, which country and city you are browsing from, etc. This information is collected anonymously and we use it in aggregated form strictly to analyse how the CORE website is used by visitors. Further information and instructions for opting out of Google Analytics tracking are available at: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**Visits to CORE Labs pages**

Before you visit the CORE Labs pages of the CORE website for the first time you will be asked to opt-in to additional privacy settings. If you agree to continue to CORE Labs pages you are giving consent for your name, name of your institution and country to be searchable by other users who have also opted-in. These users will be able to send you messages through the CORE Labs account and add you to discussion groups.

You will also receive notifications by email whenever there is activity connected with your account: when you receive a new message, when a new document has been shared, when there is a new post in a discussion you participate in, when you received an invitation to join a group, when somebody accepted your invitation to join a group, when a new member has joined the group you belong to. You can set your notifications preferences on the ‘Setting’ page of your CORE Labs account. We will hold your CORE Labs data until you notify us to delete your account.

**Your rights**

You have the right to request copies of the data held about you by CORE and the right to request this data to be withdrawn and erased. To do so, please contact us at [contact@core-econ.org](mailto:contact@core-econ.org). Please bear in mind that by requesting the erasure of your data you will lose access to additional resources.

You have the right to withdraw consent to receive further communication from CORE and to unsubscribe from receiving updates. To do so either use the unsubscribe link included in the email communication from CORE or email us at [contact@core-econ.org](mailto:contact@core-econ.org).

You have the right to complain to the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/) (ICO) if you think there is a problem with the way CORE is holding your data.

We will ensure that all personal data you supply is held in accordance with the Data Protection Act 2018 and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We do not sell or otherwise transfer personal data to any third parties or use it for any other purpose.

_We have made revisions to this Privacy Policy, effective 6 March 2019_
